♪ ♪
(girl crying)
(shuddering breath)
Come to me.
(voice shaking):
A guardian angel.
A spirit of comfort.
Spirit of any celestial sphere.
Anything.
Hear my call.
(takes deep breath)
(whispering):
Come to me.
(deep whispering voice):
You.
(gasps softly)
♪ ♪
(soft, hissing breaths)
(voice whispering indistinctly)
You wakened me from an eternity
of darkness.
(wind gusting)
You... You...
You are not for the living.
You are not for human kind.
♪ ♪
And shall you be one with me
ever-eternally?
Do you swear it?
I swear.
(inhales deeply)
(moaning softly)
- (snarls)
- (screaming)
(short, rapid breathing)
(gasps)
(rapid breathing continues)
(panting softly)
Thomas.
Thomas?
- THOMAS: What's that, my love?
- (shuddering)
What is it?
Nothing. I...
I dreamt... I...
Come here.
There's nothing
to be afraid of, hmm?
The honeymoon was yet too short.
(chuckles)
Take off your shoes.
I wish I could stay, my love.
How should I have earned
such a doting wife?
(cat meows, purrs)
- Ellen.
- (Ellen chuckles)
I told you not to let her
into bed.
Everything I wear,
absolutely covered in it.
But Greta loves it here.
She wishes you to stay, too.
Today is of
the utmost importance for us.
One minute more.
I really must be off.
Goodbye.
♪ ♪
He has the position already.
They'll send him away.
(lively chatter)
♪ ♪
THOMAS:
Morning.
Excuse me.
- (lively chatter continues)
- (panting)
- (bird screeching)
- (cattle mooing)
♪ ♪
Knock & Assoc. Estate Agents
(breathing heavily)
You have kept him
a quarter hour.
Forgive me, sir.
(man laughing in other room)
- (knocks)
- Pray, pardon me, Herr Knock,
for my tardiness.
Your delay is providential,
my boy, providential.
Come in, come in.
Still preparing the account.
Uh, and I thank you, sir,
for considering me.
When tidings of your recent
nuptials reached my ears,
I knew it was providence.
A new husband requires
new wages.
You're too generous, sir.
Allow me to extend my
congratulations to your wife.
Thank you, sir.
She truly is beautiful.
A... a nonpareil.
Almost a...
...sylph.
(laughing)
Yes. Thank you, sir.
Uh, and I'm most eager
to proceed
with whatever your request,
that I might be fully engaged
with the firm.
Indeed, indeed.
Providence.
Now, I have been entertaining
dealings with a foreign count.
Very old line of nobility.
Very old and... eccentric.
He wishes to acquire a home
here in our Wisburg.
- Oh, yes?
- To retire here.
He has one foot in the grave,
so to speak.
- (laughing)
- (Thomas chuckles)
Uh, I should be pleased
to escort the gentleman
and recommend him
to our properties.
I have already selected
Grünewald Manor.
Forgive me, sir, but is it not,
well, uh, a ruin?
He requested an old home,
and he will pay most generously.
I shall meet him tomorrow,
then-- nine of the clock?
(chuckling):
Here is the peculiarity.
He's too infirm to travel,
so you needs must
journey to him.
I see.
He lives in a small country
east of Bohemia,
isolated in the Carpathian Alps.
THOMAS:
Oh.
It will be a great adventure,
my boy.
Indeed.
Uh, may not the count execute
the deed here when he arrives?
Oh, no, it is much too urgent.
He insists we offer him
an agent...
in the flesh.
And he will reward you
handsomely, my boy, handsomely.
Secure this account,
and you will secure your...
official position in the firm.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
I shan't disappoint.
And what was the count's name?
Orlok.
(Knock chuckling)
(rain pattering)
(thunder rumbling)
♪ ♪
THOMAS: And I shall
have to set off tomorrow,
as it is a six-week journey.
But Harding has
generously agreed
to keep you till my return.
Why have you killed
these beautiful flowers?
- What?
- Nothing.
- What are you talking about?
- Forgive me.
Uh, let us put them in water.
They will only die
in a few days.
- Throw them out.
- What?
Throw them out!
(thunder rumbling)
What are you...
You cannot leave.
(sighs) What is this?
I must tell you my dream.
Ellen, we have put
these difficulties behind us.
- I must.
- Please.
No more of
your childhood memories.
- The doctors advised never...
- No.
It was our wedding.
(thunder rumbling)
Yet not in chapel walls.
Above was
an impenetrable thundercloud
outstretched beyond the hills.
The scent of the lilacs
was strong in the rain, and...
when I reached the altar...
...you weren't there.
Standing before me,
all in black,
was...
Death.
But I was so happy.
So very happy.
We exchanged vows, we embraced,
and when we turned around,
everyone was dead.
(crying):
Father and... everyone.
The stench of their bodies
was horrible.
(thunder crashes)
And...
But I'd never been so happy
as that moment...
(sobbing)
...as I held hands with Death.
- (sobbing)
- (thunder crashes)
Never speak these things aloud.
Never.
It is a trifle, a foolish dream,
just as your past fancies.
Everything is well.
It portends
something awful for us.
Look, when I return,
I will finally
make something of myself.
I shall buy us a fine house
of our own with a maidservant...
We needn't any of that.
I wish you to have
all you deserve.
You mustn't leave.
I love you too much.
(hoofbeats clopping)
(laughing):
Pray, stop.
(laughter)
(laughing): Never since
our school days, Tom.
- From my grandfather, the best.
- Uh, uh, no, I oughtn't.
Uh, it's worth celebrating
your adventure.
(chuckles) Thank you.
Mm.
- I envy you.
- Mm.
I-I envy you.
You've truly taken
your father's place now.
It's incredible.
The bloody responsibility,
it's crushing, Thomas, crushing.
Of course,
it's unseemly to complain
with all the earnings,
but the demands of the market
grow faster than
the damned shipyard.
And my two girls-- two, Tom.
I... I love them
more than the world.
And... (sighs)
speak none of this to Ellen
or my Anna, but we have
another on the way.
- Mm-hmm.
- (chuckles): Congratulations.
(both laughing)
Hey, you always were
a rutting goat.
- (Friedrich braying)
- (laughing)
- I cannot resist her.
- Mm.
And when will you two newlyweds?
When I'm no longer a pauper.
Uh, Friedrich, when I have,
I mean to say,
I shall finally
be able to return
- the moneys you loaned me.
- (scoffs) Not another word.
- Uh, and, Friedrich?
- Hmm?
Do take care of Ellen.
She nearly begged me
to remain here.
And toss aside
your fine opportunity?
THOMAS: I fear her past, uh,
melancholy returning.
FRIEDRICH: Naturally.
Her dashing young husband's
leaving her bedside cold.
(laughs)
ANNA: My sweet ones,
it's time now for bed.
- GIRLS: Papa! Papa!
- (Friedrich clears throat)
BOTH:
No!
FRIEDRICH:
Listen, then, to your mother.
ANNA: The time has simply come.
Enough now.
- Come on. All right.
- FRIEDRICH: Come.
We can't!
There is a monster in the room!
- (whimpering)
- Papa! Papa!
Don't let her feed me
to the monster.
Stab him!
Pardon us,
but I am to hunt a monster.
You're a perfect child yourself.
- Good night.
- THOMAS: Good night.
FRIEDRICH:
Up we go. Come.
CLARA:
Papa, please stay with us!
FRIEDRICH: I will stay with you
until you are fast asleep.
CLARA: I can hear him breathing
beneath my bed!
ANNA: Nonsense, my darling.
You are safe and sound.
Forgive me.
I have put these fancies
behind me.
I have.
And we have each other.
♪ ♪
(both moaning softly)
(man cackling)
(breathing heavily)
(speaking ancient language)
(grunting)
(breathing heavily,
muttering in ancient language)
(laughing)
(gasps, grunts)
Your lordship, it is entirely
as you have demanded.
He shall presently be
in thy rule,
and I shall attend thee here,
near the object of thy contract!
(whooshing)
- I'm proud of you.
- Mm.
Please keep safe.
Have you so little faith in me?
I will send you my utmost faith.
And you will write to me
every day.
I shall. I promise.
Remember, it's all for us.
♪ ♪
- I love you.
Farewell.
♪ ♪
(bell tolling)
(trembling breaths)
(slow, heavy breaths)
♪ ♪
(wind howling)
(birds chirping)
(lively chatter)
(goat bleating)
- Thank you.
- (speaks Romani)
Okay.
(upbeat Balkan folk music
playing)
- (whistles)
- (dog barking)
(children clamoring)
(clamoring continues)
I'm sorry. Sorry, no.
(laughter)
(folk music continues)
(rhythmic whistling, shouting)
(jewelry jingling rhythmically)
(music ends)
(laughing)
(others join in laughter)
(laughter continues)
(speaking Romanian)
What is all this barking?
Get out, you filthy gypsies!
You bring shame to my inn.
And you bring me trouble.
Uh, forgive me. I-I only wish
to stay one night.
I have an audience
at the castle.
Castle Orlok,
beyond the Árnyék Pass...
By God's name, never speak of
that castle.
Return to your country, foreigner.
Shut your mouths!
May the holy mind of God bugger
you!
I am weary, I-I pray you.
Go.
I will pay double the board.
I banish you, I banish you with
garlic.
(door creaks open)
♪ ♪
(woman muttering in Romanian)
Please, please don't go there.
Beware of his shadow.
The shadow covers you in a
nightmare.
Awake, but a dream.
There is no escape.
Pray.
Pray, Pray.
(spitting)
(praying in Romanian)
♪ ♪
(horse neighing in distance)
(grunts softly)
(distant chanting in Romani)
(chanting continues)
Bless this virgin child.
Bless her.
Guide our stallion to the
unclean spirit.
(trembling breaths)
(chanting continues)
(dog barking)
(distressed neighing)
The vampire!
(shouting, frightened chatter)
The vampire's grave!
The vampire!
♪ ♪
(creaking)
Find his tail!
His cloven hooves!
Silence!
(chatter quiets)
God send you burst!
(shrieks)
No, by the grace of God!
(breathing heavily)
(rooster crowing)
(wind gusting)
Hello?
My horse?
(bird calling)
(wind howling)
(panting)
- (wind gusting)
- (leaves rustling)
(wood creaking)
♪ ♪
(distant hoofbeats)
(metal clanging rhythmically)
♪ ♪
(hoofbeats and clanging
slowly grow louder)
- (horses shrieking)
- (Thomas gasping)
(thudding)
(breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
(heavy breathing continues)
(otherworldly shrieking)
(wolves snarling, yelping)
(shallow, shuddering breaths)
(heavy, rhythmic hoofbeats)
- (hoofbeats continue)
- (metal clanging)
(horses neighing)
♪ ♪
(panting softly)
(breath trembling)
♪ ♪
(chain rattling)
(doors clunk shut)
ORLOK:
You are late.
(Orlok sighs)
The midnight hour has passed.
And my attendants
have all retired.
THOMAS:
Forgive me, Count.
(panting softly)
(fire crackling)
♪ ♪
(footsteps)
ORLOK:
Leave there your conveniences.
Set out the deed and sit.
Would you not wish to wait
till morning?
I wish you to do as I request.
Yes.
Of course, sir.
Lord.
Pardon me, sir?
Your lord.
I will be addressed
as the honor of my blood
demands it.
Yes, my lord.
Forgive me, my lord.
Pray...
sit.
Thank you, my lord.
I am most impatient
to bring my eyes
on your covenant papers.
(Orlok groans)
And my correspondence
with your proprietor,
Herr Knock.
I have long awaited them.
Of course, my lord.
(Orlok taking deep,
wheezing breaths)
(liquid pouring)
Drink.
(rustling)
(deep, wheezing breaths
continue)
I have, my lord...
uh, I have questions
about the, um, unfamiliar
customs of the peasantry
and the errant wanderers.
Last night, I saw...
or, rather, I believe I saw
a band of gypsies.
They ventured to
a small birch grove and...
I fear we yet keep close
many superstitions here
that may seem backward
to a young man
of your high learning.
These gypsies,
they exhumed a corpse.
It is their filthy ritual.
What manner of ritual...
Speak not of it again!
- (wings fluttering)
- (rapid squeaking)
How I look forward to retiring
to your city of a modern mind...
(deep, wheezing breath)
...who knows nothing of
nor believes
any such morbid fairy tales.
(deep, wheezing breath)
Eat.
(trembling breaths)
You are married, Herr Hutter?
- (knife slices)
- (Thomas grunts)
(gasps) Take heed what you do.
(Orlok groaning)
It's nothing.
I might ease your wound.
- (trembling breaths)
- (Orlok groaning)
Come by the fire.
Your face shows you unwell.
(Orlok takes deep,
wheezing breath)
- (fire crackling)
- (trembling breaths)
♪ ♪
(trembling breaths continue)
(birds squawking)
CLARA:
Wait for me!
Careful, children.
Keep from that filth.
CLARA:
Catch me!
Do you ever feel at times
as if you were not...
as if you were not a person?
- Well, I...
- What I wish to say is that
you are not truly present
nor alive,
as if you were at the whim
of another, like a doll,
and someone or something
had the power
to breathe life into you,
to move you.
Well, of course we all feel
out of sorts at times.
It's not out of sorts.
It's... it's as if there is
something at play that is
too awful or grave to explain.
- God.
- No, my lovely Anna.
I...
Look at the sky.
Look at the sea.
Does it never call to you,
urge you?
Something is close at hand.
That is his power.
A gentle breeze from heaven.
Destiny!
My sweet romantic.
♪ ♪
I am not mad, Anna.
Leni.
Forgive me.
Everything I say
sounds so childish.
Your words spring
from your honest heart.
My heart is lost
without my Thomas.
Hello?
Count?
♪ ♪
(door rattling)
(deep, wheezing breaths
in distance)
(door creaking)
♪ ♪
(shuddering)
- (gasping)
- (rats squeaking)
(deep, wheezing breaths)
ORLOK:
And your signature
as solicitor.
How careless of me, my lord.
The language of my forefathers.
Of course.
A maiden's token, I see.
Your bride?
THOMAS:
Just so. It, uh...
Yes.
ORLOK:
May I?
THOMAS:
We are newly married of late.
Incidentally,
I have letters to her
I would post, if I may.
(deep, wheezing breaths)
Lilac.
What was that, my lord?
You are fortunate in your love.
It's providence,
as Herr Knock would say.
Your signature.
I pray...
you will indulge my pardon.
(clicking)
I durst not neglect
your commission.
Herr Hutter.
(coins clinking)
(breathing deeply)
♪ ♪
(continues breathing deeply)
(trembling breaths)
(short gasp)
- (exhales sharply)
- (Orlok groans)
Now are we neighbors.
It is my good fortune, my lord.
Forgive my asking, my lord,
but why such an antique
residence as Grünewald Manor?
The covenant is signed.
Of course.
Well, I thank you
and congratulate you
on your new home.
It is late.
You must wish to retire.
If I may, my lord,
i-if I may be slightly unsubtle
in my approach,
I-I wish to depart as soon as...
well, as soon as agreeable
my services rendered.
I am much...
I have been enduring
the most irregular dreams.
I fear I am taken ill.
It is a black omen
to journey in poor health.
You will remain
and well rest yourself.
THOMAS:
Uh, I must object, my lord.
ORLOK:
You will obey this, my counsel.
THOMAS:
Uh, but, my lord...
(door creaks shut)
- (rats squeaking)
- Count?
(trembling breaths)
Y-You have my locket.
(grunts)
(breathing heavily)
(wood creaking)
(gasps)
(wind whistling)
♪ ♪
(panting rapidly)
(grunting)
(grunts)
(grunting, panting)
(wind whistling)
(door rattling)
(grunts)
(panting heavily)
(grunting)
- (straining)
- (heavy creaking)
(panting)
(grunts, whimpers)
(footsteps continue
descending stairs)
♪ ♪
(breathing heavily)
(uneasy, trembling breaths)
♪ ♪
(lid scraping)
(gasping, whimpering)
(rats squeaking)
(breathing heavily)
- (grunts, whimpers)
- (snarls)
(axe clanging on floor)
- (growls)
- (Thomas whimpers)
(panicked whimpering)
(wolves snarling, yelping)
- (snarling continues)
- (banging at door)
(wolves howling)
(deep, wheezing inhale)
Your husband is lost to you.
Dream of me.
Only me.
(slow, deep breathing)
(soft, otherworldly hissing)
♪ ♪
(trembling breaths)
(Orlok hissing)
(door creaking)
(wolves growling)
(Orlok groans softly)
(slow, deep breathing)
(growls softly)
(panicked, trembling breaths)
- (wheezing breath)
- (shrieking)
(grunting, breathing weakly)
(shaky, moaning breaths)
(shrieking)
♪ ♪
(slow, rhythmic gulping)
- (clock ticking)
- (rain pattering)
In mild cases of somnambulism--
sleepwalking--
it is brought on
by a congestion of the blood.
Too much blood.
Perhaps...
perhaps she was oppressed
in a somewhat odd position
beforehand.
Yet she has had these fits
in the past.
- Troubled nerves and so on.
- I see.
Well, if it continues,
let me know, but until then,
uh, keep it from your worries,
my dear fellow.
Yes, of course.
I am disposed to recommend
that she sleep in her corset.
It encourages correct posture,
calms the womb
and revives circulation.
Yes, very well.
And, uh,
if her stirring escalates,
you can always tie her
to the bed.
(Friedrich chuckles)
(Ellen whimpering)
Oh, he's coming to me.
He's coming.
I'll increase the ether.
(whimpering continues)
(heavy, rapid breathing)
(breathing slows)
♪ ♪
(gasps)
(distant clattering)
(wolves growling)
(panicked gasping)
(wolves snarling)
(grunts, screams)
Nothing of Thomas? Nothing?
No. I mean, yes, I've received
nothing of any kind.
Not even to your...
at the shipyard?
And Herr Knock?
Still no trace of him.
His firm is in daily chaos.
I never liked that man. Never.
I shall call upon his office
myself directly.
- Please, Frau Hutter, no.
- I must discover something.
- Oh, for heaven's sake!
- But Thomas...
You cannot leave unaccompanied.
I am most sensitive
to your ardent nature
and shan't reprove you further
in this error of judgment.
I will send someone daily
until Herr Knock is found.
♪ ♪
(sighs)
(wind whistling)
Thomas is well.
I'm certain of it.
Leni, it's near sundown.
We really ought to be leaving.
Leni?
Just a moment longer.
Please.
Friedrich,
be not a churl, please.
You mustn't be swept up
in her fairy ways.
The entirety of the household
centers upon her whims.
I tire of discussing her.
Think you there is no burden
upon myself?
I love her.
She is blameless for her malady.
Forgive me, my love.
Dr. Sievers will pay her
another visit.
Let us only please talk
of something else.
(takes deep breath)
- How is our little
Friedrich, hmm? -(chuckles)
- Well, hungry as always.
- (clicks tongue)
- Like his father.
- Mm. (chuckles)
Friedrich, in public?
I cannot resist you, my love.
(Ellen screaming)
Ellen?
(Ellen screams, gasps)
ANNA:
Leni!
(gasping, grunting)
- (door bangs shut)
- New patient?
Yes, sir.
Uh, we stowed him
downstairs, sir.
I have strictly forbidden
the use of the old cells.
- Begging your pardon, sir.
- It's out of the question.
This is a modern hospital,
not a prison.
A little old soul he may look,
but on my life,
saw him screaming
and a-groaning.
Found him at
the Luther Christmas Market.
Killed three sheep
with his bare hands.
And he was eating them raw-like.
Raw!
♪ ♪
(man sobbing nearby)
(key clanking in lock)
(man laughing)
(man cackling)
(man whimpers, laughs)
(man whimpering, shuddering)
Good day, mein Herr.
I am Dr. Sievers.
- What seems to be the trouble?
- (laughing)
No trouble. (laughs)
No trouble.
Providence. Providence.
I see.
Can you tell me your name,
Herr...?
I am no one.
I am his servant.
And, um,
what do you have there?
- (pigeon cooing)
- Lives, gifts,
bestowed upon me
by his lordship.
Look, this is a pretty one.
His lordship likes
the pretty ones... (kisses)
...best.
SIEVERS:
His lordship?
He is infinity.
Eyes shining
like a jeweled diadem.
And then putrescence.
Asphyxience.
(snarling)
(grunts)
And devourence.
Now, my good fellow,
why would you do that?
- It's all right.
- (Knock grunting wildly)
No one wants to hurt you,
my dear friend.
He is coming.
Who?
Who is?
'Twas he that invoked me.
'Twas I that was chosen
to serve him,
for I know what he covets.
(giggling)
And he shall cast upon you
curses, confusion,
afflictions, rebukes,
for you have forsaken me,
and he shall reign over
all of your empty corpses.
(deep, shuddering breath)
Devourence.
Devourence!
- (snarling)
- (whistle blows)
(gasps)
(whimpering rapidly)
SIEVERS:
Harding, help me.
(Anna gasps)
These hysterical spells
come over her at nightfall
like clockwork.
- Cigar?
- No, thank you.
I... lament to tell you this.
(sniffs)
Hutter's employer, Herr Knock,
was admitted to hospital
this morning.
What?
Did you speak to him of Thomas?
- He is mad.
- Mad?
Non compos mentis.
And, Friedrich, he...
well, the wretched fellow,
while inflamed with some sort
of religious mania,
he shares a similar motto
to Frau Hutter:
"He is coming."
What?
Where the devil are you, Thomas?
♪ ♪
(panting)
(gasps, speaks Romanian)
♪ ♪
(nuns whispering)
(groaning weakly)
SIEVERS: Which brings me
to the specialist.
A man by the name of von Franz.
- Swiss.
- Swiss?
Professor
Albin Eberhart von Franz.
He is the sole person who may
be able to diagnose her.
An eminent physician
and scholar in Zurich
when I was at school,
my finest teacher.
Send a message to Zurich, then.
No, no, he...
he's here in Wisburg.
Here?
Here-here?
Why haven't you told me, man?
- Well...
- This is capital news.
Damn it, man, why didn't you
think of this before?
You see, he... von Franz is
the most learned in the field,
his mind staggering.
I'll spare no expense.
No, you misunderstand me,
Friedrich.
It has fallen hard on me
to recommend him.
He was tossed out
of the university,
laughed out of his home country.
- What?
- Grieves me to say it, but...
he became obsessed
with the work of Paracelsus,
Agrippa and the like.
I am a shipman, Sievers.
Alchemy.
Mystic philosophy.
The occult.
(chanting in Old Church Slavic)
- (chanting intensifies)
- (pained grunting)
(gasps)
No! Orlok!
(speaking Romanian)
A black enchanter
he was in life.
Solomonar.
(continues in Romanian)
The devil preserved his soul
that his corpse may walk again
in blasphemy.
(continues in Romanian)
You are lost in his shadow.
No. No, I must leave.
- I promised Ellen.
- (continues in Romanian)
Remain here.
His evil cannot enter
this house of God.
I promised I'd join the firm.
I came here to sell the count
a house in Wisburg.
(continues in Romanian)
He cannot leave here.
- He is bound for Wisburg.
- He cannot leave here.
He must return
to the cursed earth
wherein he was buried.
No! He seeks after Ellen.
I know it!
♪ ♪
(distant shouting)
(deep creaking)
Soon I will no longer be a
shadow to you.
Soon our flesh shall embrace
and we shall be as one.
Nature, increase thy thunders
(thunder crashes)
and hasten me upon the wings
of thy barbarous winds.
I have not failed your lordship!
Thy promised gift awaits!
Providence!
SIEVERS: The scientific
community is on a crusade
to prove his work
drove him to madness.
- FRIEDRICH: Hmm.
- SIEVERS: I assure you,
Harding, the professor may be
a bit unconventional,
but he will know
the source of her malady.
(man grumbling indistinctly)
(knocking)
Professor von Franz?
VON FRANZ:
Leave me be.
(man shouting in distance)
It is your former student.
VON FRANZ:
Avaunt! Begone, I say!
(door creaks open)
♪ ♪
- (von Franz muttering quietly)
- (cats meowing)
SIEVERS: Professor, please,
I should not wish to intrude.
(von Franz continues muttering)
(cat meows)
SIEVERS:
Professor, please.
VON FRANZ: I had nearly
unlocked the final key
of the
Mysteriorum Libri Quinque.
SIEVERS:
I'm sorry, Professor.
VON FRANZ:
No. No matter.
I miscalculated the stars.
Hermes will not render my
black sulfur gold this evening.
FRIEDRICH: Yes, we shan't
trouble you further.
- We must take our leave.
- SIEVERS: Just...
(muttering quietly)
Good night, Professor.
Nolite dare sanctum canibus.
♪ ♪
Neque mittatis margaritas
vestra ante porcos.
My dear young Sievers.
Or do my dying eyes deceive me?
I should've known.
Embrace me, my boy.
- I am so rejoiced to see you.
- (Sievers chuckling)
I sensed something.
It brought me to Wisburg
all these years ago.
I felt it was now
imminently approaching.
I thought it ill,
but it must have been you.
(both chuckling)
Now, what is the matter?
Ah, I see, yes.
A dear friend of yours
has some rare ailment.
Perhaps a houseguest, yes?
A young woman exhibiting
protracted fits of somnambulism.
- You look tired, young man.
- (cat meows)
Schnapps?
♪ ♪
(horse grunts)
(Thomas breathing heavily)
(grunts)
Wait! You are not yet well!
♪ ♪
(deep creaking)
- (knocking)
- Yeah?
Quick, Captain.
Back to the quarterdeck with
you.
But Vasilyev. And now Redenko.
(man screaming)
Captain, it's the plague.
(rats squeaking)
Quarantine the sick!
The Devil!
Our cargo is cursed.
(retching)
Back away! Back away!
Out! Everyone out!
Untie this child at once!
It's all I could do to keep her
from tearing the room
to ribbons.
Untie her.
You are the doctor
our Sievers spoke of?
Drugged?
I have been administering
an opiate.
She must rest by day,
for her body is in utter stress
- all the night.
- She cannot be clouded.
Step away. Step away.
My dear creature, yes,
I am he, and I am
- hither come to help you.
- (cat meows)
Is she yours?
Greta?
She has no master nor mistress.
Quite so.
I entreat you to excuse me,
but I should like to begin
my consultation presently.
You see, I have a curiosity
about you.
Dr. Sievers tells me
that you have had these spells
since childhood.
Would you describe them
to me, please?
I cannot always remember them.
As if my spirit wanders off.
Tell me what you can,
from the beginning.
Sometimes it was...
it is like a dream.
- Hmm.
- And I know things.
I always knew the contents
of my Christmas gifts.
I knew when
that my mother would pass.
Father, he would find me
in our fields within the forest
as if I was
his little changeling girl.
I see.
But as I became older,
it worsened.
I frightened him.
My touch.
I was so very alone, you see,
and I wished for comfort.
Then a presence
and the nightmares,
the epilepsies, I...
Pray, continue.
At last,
Papa found me once laying.
Unclothed, I was.
My body, my...
my flesh, I...
"Sin."
"Sin," he said.
He would have sent me to
that place. I... I shan't go.
No, no.
It all ended
when I first met my Thomas.
From our love,
I became as normal.
Yet these visions
and night wanderings
have returned to you?
I fear for him so.
Professor.
My dreams grow darker.
Does evil come from within us
or from beyond?
(clock ticking)
(wheezing)
VON FRANZ:
Her trance state is begun.
You have bled her
to decrease the congestion?
SIEVERS:
Of course.
VON FRANZ:
And her menstruations are also?
SIEVERS:
Liberal.
VON FRANZ:
Too much blood. Too much blood.
A taper, please.
(wheezing continues)
Her pupil is expanded.
It does not contract naturally
to light.
- SIEVERS: Impossible.
- VON FRANZ: A second sight.
She is no longer here.
My bag.
Forgive
the grotesque tediousness
of this demonstration.
The needle.
However, I must impress upon you
that this child is not with us.
- (Anna gasps)
- Professor, I do protest.
Restrain your protestation,
for she feels nothing.
She communes now
with another realm.
Tend to the wound, Sievers.
Now...
- Do you hear me, my child?
- (Ellen moans)
And what then do you see?
I charge you,
speak now what you see.
Enduring night.
A specter of death.
He... he spreads his shadow,
and he... he... he is coming.
Who? Who is coming to you,
my child?
- Who, damn you? Speak!
- (grunting rapidly)
Yield before
this ancient talisman!
- (Ellen gasping)
- ANNA: Professor!
I will not harm her!
- (deep, raspy breathing)
- I command you,
hearken to my voice.
By the protection of Chamuel,
Haniel and Zadkiel,
impart your speech unto me.
- (gagging)
- In the name of Eligos,
Orabas and Asmoday,
impart your speech unto me.
(inhales deeply)
(demonic voice):
I shall persist to join you
every night-- first in sleep,
then in your arms.
Everything will be mixed
with abomination, and you'll be
knee-deep in blood.
Everyone will cry.
There will be none
to bury the dead.
- You are promised to me!
- VON FRANZ: Promised?
- She means her husband!
- Promised?
Help me! Help me!
(thunder rumbling softly)
As I feared.
Well?
"Well" what, my boy?
Cannot you see?
See what?
See that she is cursed.
- Cursed?
- Yes, cursed.
This dear young creature
is possessed of some spirit.
Perhaps a demon.
I beg your pardon.
SIEVERS:
I assure you, Harding,
the professor means this
as hyperbole.
- No, I mean a demon.
- You jest.
But what of your own discoveries
of macabre
hallucination pathologies?
This is not one.
You cannot conceivably
have perceived all of this.
How should this happen to Ellen?
Demonic spirits
more easily obsess those
whose lower animal functions
dominate.
Demons like them.
They seek them out.
I do not wish to dispute you,
Professor,
but I myself have witnessed
women of nervous constitutions
invent all manner of delusion.
This is no delusion.
I believe she has always been
highly conductive
to these cosmic forces,
uniquely so.
Your lunatic, perhaps.
Do you then acknowledge a
connection between these cases?
That is the question.
Oh, this is just capital.
I tell you, it is the manner
of her husband's disappearance.
No. This evil--
what it is,
how it has been summoned,
unleashed, I know not,
but this remarkable child
it has chained itself to
is in grave peril.
I must to my studies.
Frau Harding.
Sit with her. Observe her.
Report her behavior.
Sievers, no more ether.
But she will rave all the night.
Then rave she must.
There is a dread storm rising.
(wind whistling)
(men grunting)
I will end this plague. This
devil.
♪ ♪
(creaking)
(wind whistling)
(trembling breaths)
(thunder crashes)
(deep creaking)
(creaking continues)
(trembling breaths continue)
(thunder crashes)
(grunting)
(rats squeaking)
- (shrieks)
- (yelling)
(screams)
- KNOCK: Help me. Help me!
- ORDERLY: Oh, dear. Oh, my.
- (Knock whimpers, screams)
- (thunder crashes)
I'll get you out.
- Don't you worry.
- (whimpers)
Help.
It's all right. It's all right.
- Listen.
- What was that?
- (grunts)
His lordship-- he has come!
(pained screaming)
The blood is the life.
(cackling)
He's here. He's here!
His lordship is here!
- (thunder crashes)
- (cackling)
The blood is the life!
(ship creaking)
♪ ♪
(thunder crashes)
(gasps) He's here!
(gasping)
ANNA:
Ellen?
(rain pattering)
(thunder rumbling)
(horse neighing)
ELLEN:
Thomas!
(horse neighing)
- (grunts)
- (Ellen whimpers)
ELLEN:
No, no!
Thomas!
Thomas.
(groaning quietly)
(breathing heavily)
THOMAS:
He hasn't found you.
I-I feared
I'd never see you again.
My love.
(voice shaking):
You were right.
You were.
He... he has your locket.
Thomas.
- Thomas.
- (bell jingling)
FRIEDRICH:
What the hell is it now?
- Thomas!
- FRIEDRICH: Hartmann, the door!
HARTMANN:
Very good, sir.
- Thomas!
- (knocking at door)
CLARA (in distance):
Mama! Papa!
Is that the monster?
What the devil is this?
It's past 3:00 in the morning.
(bell clanging)
(wood creaking)
(rats squeaking)
FRIEDRICH:
My God.
Plague. It's a plague ship.
(squeaking continues)
FRIEDRICH:
Damn it.
Alert the port authority.
- And fetch Dr. Sievers.
- Aye, aye, sir.
(Knock laughing)
There it is, your lordship.
(laughs) There it is.
(laughing continues)
(metal creaking)
(thunder rumbling)
♪ ♪
(Orlok takes deep,
wheezing breath)
The broker lives.
I shall stifle out
the bridegroom, your lordship.
I have use in him.
Pray...
Instruct me.
Charge me. Use me.
(Orlok taking deep,
groaning breaths)
I shall fetch unto thee
thy pretty belonging?
The compact commands
she must willingly
repledge her vow.
She cannot be stolen.
Yet, my lord...
I beg thee...
ORLOK:
Silence, dog!
Your entreaties grow insolent.
You shall crave of me nothing.
My lord. (whimpers)
Daybreak draws near.
Anon, the bells of dawn
shall toll in despair
of my coming.
(sniffs deeply)
And I shall taste of you.
- (bell tolling)
- (rats squeaking)
(distant shouting)
(bell chiming)
How is he faring?
I fear no better than everyone
tells me I have suffered.
Pray, forgive me for all
the troubles I have caused you.
I am only glad you have
become yourself again.
It seems a miracle.
Perhaps Professor Franz
was wrong.
Perhaps it was only your wish
to see Thomas returned
and your... your...
My melancholy?
- Uh, I...
- Thomas has seen
something awful.
If only I could speak
to the profess...
Hush.
His thoughts are so queer.
Professor Franz said a demon.
Leni, please.
For the sake of the children.
Christmastide is upon us.
Why must you remain
so exasperatingly contrary?
Because I am in the right.
Sievers, I requested conference
with your maniac,
not a dead man.
I beg your patience, Professor,
but this is what vexes me.
He exhibits all the signs
of a blood plague.
Sepsis, ophthalmic discharge.
Even flagrant rodent bites
here and here.
I fear this ship has brought
the plague to Wisburg.
And what is confounding is
his body is
entirely absent of blood.
Look at this curious mark here.
Huh.
I've seen some leviathan-like
pests in our canals,
but tell me, Professor,
what rat has jaws of such size?
Angels and demons protect us.
Where is your lunatic?
You must take me to him
presently.
Ain't you heard, Doctor, sir?
SIEVERS:
No.
Herr Knock has gone and escaped.
SIEVERS:
What?
He killed the porter on duty
last night.
This man must be found.
Sirrah, show me out.
Sievers, fetch Harding.
And meet me
at my residence tonight.
This is no mere plague.
(Orlok whispering
in ancient language)
♪ ♪
(voices wailing, screaming)
(Thomas breathing shakily)
(Thomas grunts softly)
Get off me.
(grunts) Give me room.
- Thomas.
- (gasping)
- I-I can't breathe.
- It's me.
(gasps) I-I can't breathe.
- (Orlok snarls)
- Get off!
(breathing heavily)
Please you,
don't leave us, Mama.
ANNA: I promise I shan't let
anything harm you.
No monsters. Nothing.
Now, give me a kiss.
And say your prayers.
(music box playing
"O Tannenbaum")
BOTH:
Now I lay me down to sleep,
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
(music box continues
playing quietly)
(clock ticking)
- (soft thudding, creaking)
- (gasps softly)
(soft, trembling breaths)
(quiet creaking)
- Anna?
- (gasps, screams)
Oh. Oh, you frightened me.
Forgive me.
Has Friedrich returned?
Uh, uh, no. No.
What is it, my lovely?
May I...
stay with you tonight?
Our friendship is
a precious balm to my heart.
(kisses)
(sighs) Forgive my chiding you.
Thank you for loving me.
(Anna chuckles softly)
You may take it if you wish.
God is with us, Leni.
I cannot yield
to being haunted by a ghost.
Oh, no, please. No.
It is no mere ghost,
for it can manifest physically
and with the most foul intent.
And what, pray, is that?
Like every plague,
its soul desire
is to consume all life on Earth.
This creature is a force
more powerful than evil.
It is Death itself.
I have not slept in days.
My house has become a bedlam,
and here I've been resummoned
to this godforsaken habitation
for this?
Do not tell me you believe
in such medieval devilry!
I do not believe. I know!
I have seen things in this world
that would've made
Isaac Newton crawl
back into his mother's womb.
We have not become
so much enlightened
as we have been blinded by
the gaseous light of science.
I have wrestled with the devil
as Jacob wrestled the angel
in Peniel.
And I tell you,
if we are to tame darkness,
we must first face
that it exists.
Meine Herren,
we are here encountering
the undead plague carrier,
the Vampyr Nosferatu.
(breathing deeply)
♪ ♪
- (window opens)
- (wind howling)
(gasps)
(thunder rumbling)
ELLEN:
You.
I have felt you
crawling like a serpent
in my body.
It is not me.
It is your nature.
No. I love Thomas.
Love is inferior to you.
I told you,
you are not of humankind.
You are a villain to speak so.
I am an appetite.
Nothing more.
(inhales deeply)
O'er centuries,
a loathsome beast
I lay within the darkest pit.
Till you did wake me,
enchantress,
and stirred me from my grave.
You are my affliction.
I care nothing
of your afflictions.
Yet even now we are fated.
Your husband has signed his name
and covenanted you to my person
for but a sack of gold.
- Lies.
- For gold,
he did absolve his nuptial bond.
You know nothing of him.
And the resignation
must be completed by you
freely of thine own will.
You are a deceiver.
You deceive yourself.
I was but an innocent child.
And thought you
I would not return?
Thought you I would not?
Your passion is bound to me.
You cannot love.
I cannot.
Yet I cannot be sated
without you.
Remember how once we were?
A moment. Remember?
(both breathing deeply)
I abhor you.
You are false!
So you wish me to prove
my enmity as well?
I will leave you three nights.
Tonight was the first.
Tonight you denied yourself,
and thereby, you suffer me
to vanish up the lives
of those you love.
Denied myself?
You revel in my torture.
Upon the third night,
you will submit,
or he you call your husband
shall perish by my hand.
No.
Till you bid me come
shall you watch the world
become as naught.
- No!
- (shrieks)
(rapid, gasping breaths)
(trembling breaths nearby)
- (Anna moaning)
- (rats squeaking)
(screaming)
Two more nights.
- (screaming)
- (frantic chatter)
NURSE:
I ain't never seen the like.
It's been a-spreading faster
than wildfire since yestermorn.
We simply cannot admit any more.
The contraction rate
is too high.
I've entreated the burgomaster
for a quarantine.
- The city must be shut up.
- It ain't Christian.
We can find rooms, sir.
The day of judgment's
a-coming, sir. Take pity.
SIEVERS: We must remain calm
in the face of this plague.
(inhales sharply)
(breathing heavily):
A shadow pressing.
My body sinking.
Sinking.
(whimpers)
The smell of rancid meat.
(whimpers, inhales deeply)
Suffocating.
(gasping)
I...
I feel so weak. I...
(laughing)
I fear little Friedrich
is so strong,
so hungry he is eating me weary.
(short, gasping breaths)
May I... may I see the girls?
(giggling)
I must assure them...
(sobbing softly)
Everything will be well,
my darling.
Everything shall be just fine.
I don't know myself.
♪ ♪
Ellen, tell me,
what is this
insufferable darkness?
I...
(pained gasping)
(lock clicks)
Herr Harding, you must see me.
There is something.
The shadow,
an infernal creature.
- Ellen.
- Please!
These are no troubled nerves.
It is as Professor Franz
described-- a demon.
Frau Hutter, forgive me,
but I need you and Thomas--
both of you-- to return home.
What?
It's for your own sake.
Please.
Have pity.
Thomas is very poorly.
I know not what I...
I shall pray for Tom.
- You know I love you both.
- What of Anna?
Did you not see her?
It's none of your concern.
Friedrich,
you must listen to me.
We're all in
the most grave danger.
I throw myself at your feet!
Frau Hutter, please!
Why do you hate me?
How dare you speak to me
in that marked manner?
You have never liked me. Never.
Know your place, madam.
I will not stand by and pretend
at your superiority.
I refuse to exchange
- reproaches with you.
- Why can you not hear me?
Listen to me, please!
I have done everything
in my power
to be kind to you
in these long months.
Tied me up.
Find the dignity to display
the respect to your caretaker.
How can you be so stupid
and cruel?
Hartmann will call you a coach.
My expense, of course.
And for your husband's sake,
I pray you learn
to conduct yourself
with more deference.
Anna is going to die.
You are going to die!
We're all going to die!
Why did you not tell me
of this before?
SIEVERS:
I am a fool.
Of course it is Herr Knock.
His obsessive consumption
of living creatures--
it must be him.
He is not Nosferatu.
But he must be found,
for he has made compact
with this shadow.
VON FRANZ:
Search everything.
Pull up the rug.
Solomonari.
And their codex of secrets.
(indistinct chatter,
people sobbing)
MAN: "Then I stood
on the sand by the sea.
"And I saw a beast
rising out of the sea.
"And the serpent gave
the beast authority...
(dog barking nearby)
"...to speak of great names
in blasphemy.
(rats squeaking)
"And the beast had
the form of a leopard,
"the feet of a bear,
the mouth of a lion!
"A beast with seven heads
and ten horns!
"On each horn a crown,
on each head
a blasphemous name..."
- (voice fades in distance)
- (trembling breaths)
Our somnambulist and her husband
are in incomparable danger.
I must see them.
I sent them home.
How can this perversion
be killed?
I do not know.
You sent them home?
- What?
- You sent them home?
No, not that. Yes, I did.
You don't know?
Precisely. Correct.
I do not know.
I have never encountered
Nosferatu firsthand.
He doesn't know.
All your fine lectures
are mere regurgitations
from bloody books!
The means of repelling
and destroying
vary greatly
from region to region.
Their efficacy
is plainly unknown.
Yet there is one invariable fact
- that interests me most.
- Go on.
In every account,
the Nosferatu must return
to the earth
wherein it was buried
by first crow of cock.
It must sleep
in its grave by day.
What happens if it does not?
That, my dear Sievers,
is the question.
FRIEDRICH (laughing):
Oh, God.
My God.
I am shattering.
I'm breaking apart. Get out.
- SIEVERS: Har-Harding.
- Take your leave at once.
Both of you!
SIEVERS: Friedrich, please,
we do not wish to...
Can't you see there's a bloody
real plague, gentlemen?
A real epidemic that is
really killing real people.
- Damn you, Harding!
- Oh, the pair of you!
I'm sorry, Sievers. I'm sorry.
Frau Hutter is mad
and should have been
locked up long ago.
My Anna...
was bitten by vermin.
Rats! No more.
Tomorrow,
we are leaving Wisburg.
But the quarantine-- tomorrow,
we close off the city.
I'm not gonna let
your vain madness kill my wife.
The night demon has supped
of your good wife's blood
and shall return for the rest.
(scoffs)
Leave.
(takes deep breath)
♪ ♪
- (grunts softly)
- (Ellen breathing heavily)
ELLEN:
Oh, Thomas.
Ellen, my love.
We must go.
We must flee the city.
You're in danger.
- You knew...
- We cannot run.
No, we must.
There is something
I must tell you.
Something so loathsome, so base.
Nothing you can say
will shake me,
for there is a devil
in this world,
and I have met him, and he...
I cannot speak it. He...
He is come to Wisburg for you.
I know.
What?
I know him.
Know him?
I've brought this evil upon us.
I have never shared my...
secret with any soul.
I sought company.
I sought...
tenderness, and I called out.
- What do you mean by this?
- At first, it was sweet.
- I had never known such bliss.
- Ellen.
(crying):
Yet it turned to torture.
It would kill me.
But, Thomas...
it was you that gave me the
courage to be free of my shame.
You.
What are you telling me?
Don't you understand?
Pray, help me to.
He is my shame.
He is my melancholy.
He took me as his lover then,
and now he has come back.
He has discovered our marriage
and has come back.
Impossible.
He stalks me in my dreams.
All my sleeping thoughts
are of him every night.
- Ellen.
- Don't touch me!
I am not to be touched.
(takes deep breath)
You stopped your letters to me.
What?
You promised to write to me
every day.
Did not you think of me
in that castle?
I did. I...
Lies.
After what you have
just confessed, how...
He told me about you.
He told me how foolish you were.
How fearful.
How like a child.
How you fell into his arms
as a swooning lily of a woman.
Ellen.
He told me how you sold me
to him for gold.
- No, I... -Our love was
supposed to be sacred!
- Ellen, please.
- You never listen!
Well, where is it?
Your money?
Your promotion? Your house?
Where is that
which is so precious to you?
Have you paid back kind Harding
your debt?
Have you repaid him with this
plague that infects his wife?
I left for us, for our future.
For what? For what?
For these things!
- For you!
- It doesn't matter!
It doesn't matt...
Can't you see?
We should never have married.
We're already dead!
(screaming)
- Ellen, please.
- (raspy breathing)
(wheezy groaning)
(groaning stops)
(deep, gasping breaths)
(strained breathing)
Ellen!
(strained breathing continues)
I-I shall send for Dr. Sievers.
No!
No! Please, please.
I'll be good.
I promise. I promise.
(breathing heavily)
(short, rapid breathing)
You could never please me
as he could.
♪ ♪
- ELLEN: Yes! Take me!
- (Thomas grunts)
(Ellen breathing heavily)
ELLEN:
Please.
Please!
- (Thomas grunting)
- Yes!
(Ellen grunting)
Kiss me.
Kiss my heart. My heart.
(grunting continues)
Let him see.
Let him see our love.
(grunting continues)
- (shrieks)
- (Thomas gasps)
(Ellen laughing)
Without you,
I will become a demon.
- Ellen. Ellen! Ellen!
- (Ellen gasping rapidly)
Ellen, it's me. Ellen.
Ellen, I love you. I love you.
You're safe with me.
It's me. It's me.
- (Ellen sobbing)
- (Thomas breathing heavily)
Keep away from me.
I am unclean.
Never.
He will murder you
if I do not go to him.
We will be torn apart,
and the world will be despair.
No.
I'll kill him.
Kill him I will.
He shall never harm you again.
Never.
- (wind howling)
- (fire crackling)
VON FRANZ:
At last.
"And lo, the maiden fair
"did offer up her love
unto the beast
"and with him lay
in close embrace
"until the first cock crow.
"Her willing sacrifice
thus broke the curse
and freed them from
the plague of Nosferatu."
She is the way.
(shivering breaths)
Wake not.
- CLARA: Papa! Papa!
- (Anna gasping)
- Friedrich. Friedrich!
- (muttering sleepily)
(girls screaming)
Friedrich, wake up.
- (whimpering)
- (girls continue screaming)
(screaming continues)
- (snarling bite)
- (screaming stops)
(screams)
(growls)
(Anna whimpering)
(Orlok growls softly)
(wood creaking)
(shuddering breaths)
I can weep no longer, for
I have no more tears to shed.
We must speak with him.
Just a moment longer.
His grief is too great.
May I?
More will be taken.
- She was with child.
- I know.
The grim reaper wields
his heavy scythe
with every change of wind.
Professor,
I must speak with you.
And I would speak with you.
Take that blackguard
from this place!
- Your diseased mind...
- Please. Please.
...has brought
all of this outrage!
- Stop this.
- Stop, please. It is my fault.
This moment doesn't
concern you, Thomas.
- Your very presence... -Your
horror has rent our hearts,
- but you must hear us.
- ...does me wrong!
Friedrich,
these nightmares do exist!
They exist.
And yet he shows no sign
of the blood plague.
The good sisters sought
to nurse me
back to health
with their prayer,
yet I fear I'm not free
of his spell.
Trust in God and your strength.
The monster left you to
the wolves, yet you prevailed.
Harding.
Forgive me.
I'm not myself. I...
Please forgive me, all of you.
My reason could not accept...
accept...
Strength, man. Strength.
Orlok has kept his coffin
within Grünewald Manor?
- Assuredly.
- Under our very noses.
Tonight, we destroy the beast.
- Let me come with you.
- No, of course not, Ellen.
You must be kept safe away.
We shall meet at Harding's
and depart for the manor.
Please. The readiness is all.
We shall sanctify the earth
wherein he is buried
and destroy the sarcophagus.
Then he can have no sanctuary
at cock crow.
And when we uncover the body?
I will drive a spike
of cold iron through him.
- What if it does not work?
- It must.
Professor, allow me to walk you
to your door.
I know...
it must be me, Professor.
I am but an able tourist
in this occult world.
You were born to it.
It is a rare gift.
His pull to me is so powerful,
so terrible,
yet my spirit cannot
be evil as his.
We must know evil
to be able to destroy it.
We must discover it
within ourselves.
And when we have, we must
crucify the evil within us,
or there is no salvation.
I need no salvation.
My entire life, I have done
no ill but heed my nature.
Then hearken to it.
I fear Nosferatu is impervious
to any of our iron stakes.
I'm convinced only you
have the faculty to redeem us.
THOMAS:
Ellen, let us make haste.
In heathen times,
you might have been
a great priestess of Isis.
Yet, in this strange
and modern world,
your purpose is
of greater worth.
You are our salvation.
Thank you.
I will keep your husband
at bay tonight.
Go now. Go home.
Attend him that he is sturdy
for this false hunt.
♪ ♪
(wind whistling)
(deep, trembling breaths)
You will put an end
to all of this?
Promise you shan't return to me
till he is no more.
- Promise me you won't return.
- I promise.
He does not have power
over you, Thomas.
I place my utter faith in you.
I love you.
Fear not.
(footsteps receding)
(whispers):
Goodbye.
He is not here?
No, Mr. Harding
has departed, sir.
Where could he have gone?
He has a heavy grief.
- We shall wait for him.
- (bell tolling in distance)
There's time yet till sundown.
No, we must find him.
He is unwell, Sievers.
I fear for him.
- SIEVERS: Harding!
- THOMAS: Harding!
(dogs barking)
THOMAS:
Friedrich!
♪ ♪
(keys jingling)
(lock clanks)
(deep, shuddering breaths)
Clara.
(crying):
Louise.
(sniffles, whimpers)
Oh, my girls.
Anna.
Your bed is so dark.
So small.
(coughs)
Anna, my love.
Our son.
Our little son.
Forgive me.
I shall never sleep again.
- Never.
- (lid thuds)
(trembling breaths)
Let this, your tender embrace,
keep me now in bliss,
away from everlasting sleep.
(panting)
Friedrich!
Oh, God.
VON FRANZ:
We are too late.
We must set fire
to their infected bodies.
Our flames will sanctify them.
I cannot bear any more.
Please, we must onward.
But Orlok-- will he not
already have risen?
Should we not return
to our homes?
No, I will not wait
till morning.
VON FRANZ:
Very wise, young Thomas.
(sighs) I feel his hold
upon me this night.
May God have mercy
on their souls.
VON FRANZ:
"In the Name of Jehovah,
"and by the power and dignity
of these three Names,
"Tetragrammaton,
Anexhexeton, Primematum,
"cast thee, O thou disobedient
Spirit Nosferatu,
"into the Lake of Fire,
"there to remain
until the Day of Doom
"and not to be remembered
before the face of God
"who shall come to judge
the quick and the dead
and the world with fire."
♪ ♪
(indistinct chanted vocal over
dramatic orchestral score)
Behold, the third night.
(grunts)
There is a chapel
beyond the courtyard.
VON FRANZ:
Make haste, Thomas!
(wind howling)
ELLEN (whispering):
I am ready.
I bid you, come to me.
- (grunts)
- (door creaking)
(panting)
(rats squeaking)
There he lies.
(squeaking intensifies)
SIEVERS:
Oh, God.
(grunting, gasping)
Go forward, Thomas.
Set free the demon's body.
- (rat shrieks viciously)
- (grunts)
♪ ♪
(Sievers grunting)
- (Thomas yells)
- SIEVERS: Thomas, no!
- (gurgling)
- Herr Knock.
I...
relinquished him my soul.
I should have been
the Prince of Rats, immortal.
But he cares only
for his pretty bride,
- and she is his.
- Monstrous.
Strike again.
I am blasphemy.
Die, you accursed
mis-birth of hell!
- (rats squeaking)
- Set fire to it all.
Damn it, man,
he has gone to my wife.
VON FRANZ:
We must burn it.
We must destroy
all his habitation.
No sanctuary.
No, there is no time to be lost.
- He pursues Ellen.
- It must be her!
He cannot resist her blood!
SIEVERS:
You are a madman.
You knew Orlok
would not be here.
You knew it this afternoon.
Your wife wills it.
This is not moral!
God is beyond our morals!
(laughs)
In vain! In vain!
You run in vain!
You cannot outrun her destiny!
Her dark bond with the beast
shall redeem us all,
for when the sun's pure light
shall break upon the dawn,
redemption!
(rats shrieking frantically)
The plague shall be lifted!
Redemption!
♪ ♪
(slow, deep breathing)
(sighs softly)
You accept this of your own
will?
(Orlok inhales slowly)
- I do.
- (Orlok exhales)
Then the covenant is fulfilled.
Your oath re-pledged.
Yes.
so too shall be our flesh.
You are mine.
(both breathing heavily)
♪ ♪
(Ellen moaning softly)
(both breathing heavily)
(heavy breathing continues)
♪ ♪
(Ellen moaning)
- (Orlok bites)
- (whimpers)
(breathing heavily, whimpering)
(Orlok gulping)
♪ ♪
(panting)
(slow, deep breaths)
(weakly):
More.
(whimpers weakly)
(Orlok gulping)
(rooster crows)
(Orlok gasps)
(Orlok groaning)
(soft, gasping breaths)
(retches)
♪ ♪
(Ellen breathing shakily)
(Orlok groaning)
(shrieking)
(shriek fades)
(breathing weakly)
THOMAS:
Ellen.
(bell tolling in distance)
(Ellen's breathing stops)
(Thomas breathing shakily)
(sobbing softly)
♪ ♪
VON FRANZ:
Forgive us.
"And lo, the maiden fair
"did offer up her love
unto the beast
"and with him lay
in close embrace
"until the first cock crow.
"Her willing sacrifice
thus broke the curse
and freed them from
the plague of Nosferatu."
♪ ♪
(music ends)